Guide to the Baptist Church of Hornby records, 1860-1916.
Baptist Church of Hornby records, 1860-1916
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Baptist Church of Hornby records, 1860-1916.
6074
Baptist Church of Hornby (Hornby, N.Y.)
1 reel microfilm.
Microfilm
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Covenant and annual meeting minutes interspersed with membership records. Subjects discussed include revivals, the appointment of pastors, and church discipline.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The early history of this congregation as related by William G. Gardner (see the accessions folder) is unclear. Apparently a number of congregations from the area around Hornby Forks including Dryun, Jersey, Catlin, Mead's Creek, Campbell (then West Hill) and Erwin had formed congregations which contributed members to the Hornby Church at its formation between 1825 and 1838. In 1840 the Mead's Creek Baptist Church was set off from Hornby as a separate congregation. The church originally belonged to the Steuben Association but by 1847 had joined the Chemung River Baptist Association which met in Hornby in 1860. After 1862 the Hornby church had a Sunday school.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Records of the Hornby Baptist Church (1860-1916) contain monthly covenant and annual meeting minutes interspersed with membership lists which are revised periodically between i860 and 1895. Minutes deal mainly with the condition of the church, the election of trustees, church discipline, and procuring ministers. In the back of the volume are minutes of the Chemung River Baptist Association in 1865 and the Program of the 67th Annual meeting held in 1909. Some entries are illegible.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Baptist Church of Hornby (Hornby, N.Y.); Baptist Church of Mead's Creek (Mead's Creek, N.Y.); Chemung River Baptist Association (N.Y.); Steuben Baptist Association (N.Y.)
Subjects:
Baptists--Education.; Church records and registers--New York (State)--Hornby.; Church discipline.; Baptists--New York (State)--Hornby.; Revivals--New York (State)--Hornby.
Places:
Steuben County (N.Y.)--Religious life and customs.; Hornby (N.Y.)--Religious life and customs.
Form and Genre Terms:
Minutes.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Record Book, 1860-1916
  Contains monthly covenant meeting and annual meeting minutes with membership information interspersed. They record the appointment of pastors, the receiving and dismissal of members, congregational discipline, and occasionally, church policy. Membership lists and items of note in the meeting minutes are as follows:
  - Inside front cover
    List of months and money.
  - Inside front cover
    List of officers of the Baptist Church and Society
  - Inside front cover
    Trustees and Ministerial Committee, l866-l880.
  - Page 1, 1860
    List of male members with date of death noted.
  - Page 2-3, 1860
    List of female members with "notes."
  - Page 90, Aug. 3, 1880
    List of male members with remarks, con't.
  - Page 91, Aug. 3, 1880
    List of female members with remarks, con't.
  - Page 112, Aug. 7, 1883
    List of male members with remarks.
  - Page 113, Aug. 7, 1883
    List of female members with remarks.
  - Page 114, Aug. 7, 1883
  - Page 115, Aug. 7, 1883
  - Page 148, Feb. 1892
    List of male members.
  - Page l49, Feb. 1892
    List of female members.
  - Page 161, ?
  - Page 162, ?
  - Page 192, Sept. 1892
  - Page 193, Sept. 1892
  - Page 216, Sept. 1895
  - Page 217-218, Sept. 1895
  - Page 5, May 5, 1860
    Covenant meeting minutes commence.
  - Page 5, July 7, 1860
    Visit by the American Home Mission Society agent.
  - Page 6, Sept. 1860
    Church hosted the Meeting of the Chemung River Baptist Association.
  - Page 18, May 3, 1862
    A Sunday School is organized
  - Page page 28, date. Dec. 21, 1864
    contents Ordination of Bro. F. G. Surbridge.
  - Page 34, Apr. 7, 1866
    Discussion of how to achieve a revival.
  - Page 58, Dec. 4&5, 1873
    Discussion of whether or not to have a revival.
  - Page 67, Aug. 26, 1876
    Voted that the meeting house not be used for political meetings.
  - Page 119, Dec. 18, 1883
    Covenant and Articles of Faith of the Baptist Publishing Society at Philadelphia are adopted by the congregation.
  - Page 120, Jan. 1884
    Female members are given the right to participate in and vote on all transactions of the church.
  - Page 128, Apr. 1865-Sept.
    No meetings.
  - Page 128, 1865 Sept. 1865- Jan.
  - Page 128, 1886
  - Page 128, Jan.-Apr. 1886
  - Page 137, Apr. 1887
    After a slump new members begin to come in.
  - Page 142-143
    Pages are out of order.
  - Page 196-197
    Statistics for 1905.
  - Page 260-261
    Program of the 67th Annual Meeting of the Chemung River Baptist Association, 1909.
  - Page 26l
    Minutes of the 23rd Anniversary of the Chemung River Baptist Association, 1865.
  - Page 261-362
    Blank.
  - Page 363, May 4, 1907
    Last minutes